第 8 章：TH。TH 是爆破音。舌尖要牢牢压在
Chapter 8, TH. TH is a popped sound. The tongue tip is pressed firmly behind the
上牙后方。我想让你暂时把单词想成石头。
top teeth. I'd like you to consider words as rocks for a moment. When a rock first
浪花刚卷进海里时，边缘清晰而分明。翻滚几次之后，
rolls into the ocean, it is sharp and well-defined. After tumbling about for a few
一个词经历了类似的过程。
millennia, it becomes round and smooth. A word goes through a similar process. When
刚进入英语时，它可能有很多尖锐、清楚的元音，或
it first rolls into English, It may have a lot of sharp, well-defined vowels or
但经过几百万张嘴反复说出来之后，它会变得圆润、
consonants in it, but after rolling off of a few million tongues, it becomes round
这种平滑过程会在紧元音被弱化、变小，
and smooth. This smoothing process occurs when a tense vowel becomes reduced and
无声辅音变成有声辅音时，也会发生这种平滑。最常见的词最平滑，
when an unvoiced consonant becomes voiced. The most common words are the smoothest,
有几种非常常见的单词，
the most reduced, the most often voiced. There are several very common words that
里面的 TH 都是有声的：this、that、the、those、them、they、there、then，
are all voiced, this, that, the, those, them, They, there, there, then, then,
though。think 或 thing 这类强词，以及较长或不常见的词，
though. The strong words such as think, think, or thing, as well as long or
例如 thermometer 或 theologian，其中的 TH 保持清音。
unusual words such as thermometer or theologian, stay unvoiced. The sound of
TH 这个组合似乎只存在于英语、希腊语和卡斯蒂利亚西班牙语中。
the TH combination seems to exist only in English, Greek, and Castilian Spanish.
和大多数其他辅音一样，它也有两种：有声和无声。
Just as with most of the other consonants, there are two types, voiced and unvoiced.
有声 TH 像 D，但不是在牙齿后方，而是向下、向前约四分之一英寸，
The voiced TH is like a D, but instead of being in back of the teeth, it's a quarter
放在两齿之间。无声 TH 像是在牙齿之间发 S。
inch lower and forward between the teeth. The unvoiced TH is like an S between the
大多数人倾向于用 S 或 T 替代清 TH，
teeth. Most people tend to replace the unvoiced TH with S or T, and the voiced
TH 换成 Z 或 D。所以他们不说 thing，而说 sing 或 ting；不说 that，
one with Z or D. So instead of thing, they say sing or ting, and instead of that,
他们会说 zat 或 dat。要正确发 TH，想象蛇的舌头。
they say zat or dat. To pronounce TH correctly, think of a snake's tongue. You
不要把一条又大又放松的舌头长长地伸出口外，
don't want to take a big relaxed tongue, throw it out of your mouth for a long
也不要让它停在那里太久；只做一个非常快速、尖锐的小动作。
distance and leave it there for a long time. Make only a very quick, sharp little
让舌尖保持非常紧绷。它会在牙齿之间快速伸出。
movement. Keep your tongue's tip very tense. It darts out between your teeth and
然后很快弹回来：thing、that、this。发
snaps back very quickly. Thing. That. This. The tongue's position for the
无声 TH 时，舌头位置类似 S，但 TH 的舌头会伸到
unvoiced TH is similar to that of S, But for th the tongue is extended through the
牙齿之间，而不是在牙齿后方发嘶音；有声 TH 有点像 D，
teeth instead of hissing behind the back of the teeth The voice th is like a d
区别只在于舌头放在牙齿之间，甚至压在牙齿后方。
except that the tongue is placed between the teeth or even pressed behind the teeth
现在我们准备好做一些练习了。
Now we're ready for some practice